{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. When acceleration is _______, velocity of a particle is constant.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Zero",
        "b": "Maximum",
        "c": "None of the above",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. In a closed loop control system with positive value of feedback gain, the overall gain of the system will ___",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Decrease",
        "b": "Increase",
        "c": "Be unaffected",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. A simple mass spring damper system having natural frequency &omega;<sub>n</sub>. If the spring stiffness is halved and mass is doubled, what will be its natural frequency?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2&omega;<sub>n</sub>",
        "b": "&omega;<sub>n</sub>/2",
        "c": "4&omega;<sub>n</sub>",
        "d": "8&omega;<sub>n</sub>"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. A block whose mass is 4kg is fastened with a spring constant k = 64 N/m. The block is pulled from its equilibrium position on a frictionless surface and released. The period of the resulting motion in seconds is ___",
      "answers": {
        "a": "&#960;/2",
        "b": "2&#960;",
        "c": "&#960;/4",
        "d": "&#960;"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The natural frequency of a mass spring damper system is &omega;<sub>n</sub>. The natural frequency of this system in the moon will be __",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.408 &omega;<sub>n</sub>",
        "b": "0.204 &omega;<sub>n</sub>",
        "c": "1.167 &omega;<sub>n</sub>",
        "d": "&omega;<sub>n</sub>"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "6. The time period of a mass spring damper system depends on ____",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Mass of the block",
        "b": "Spring Constant",
        "c": "Both of the above",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },	
	
	{
      "question": "7. The time period of a mass, suspended from a spring is 'T'. If the spring is cut into 4 equal parts and same mass is suspended from one of the parts, then the new time period will be,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "T",
        "b": "2T",
        "c": "T/4",
        "d": "T/2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "8. When a system is vibrating in a normal mode,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "All masses move with the same Amplitude and same Frequency",
        "b": "All masses move with the same Amplitude and different Frequency",
        "c": "All masses move with different Frequency but of same phase",
        "d": "All masses move with the same frequency and maintain a fixed phase relation"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	
	{
      "question": "9. A mass of 0.5 kg is suspended in a vertical plane by a spring having a stiffness coefficient of 300 N/m. The mass is displaced vertically downward from its static equilibrium position through a distance of 0.01 m . Find the natural frequency of the system.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "24.5 Hz",
        "b": "31.6 Hz",
        "c": "5.1 Hz ",
        "d": "3.9 Hz"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "10. The natural frequency of a single degree of freedom system decreases when the mass ____",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increases",
        "b": "Decreases",
		"c": "Does not have any effect",
        "d": "None of the above"
		
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "11. For an under damped system, the damping ratio is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Less than one",
        "b": "Greater than one",
		"c": "Equal to one",
        "d": "None of the above"
		
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
	
  ]
}
